# Vishwas Reddy Mothukpally

www.linkedin.com/in/vishwas-mothukpally

Cell Phone: (435) 757-2458 Email: <u>vishwasred@gmail.com</u>

A transportation engineer with project experience is working for City of Philadelphia and Pennsylvania Department of Transportation. Leading traffic Microsimulation projects, experienced in On-field Traffic observations and data collections and assisting with engineering CAD design projects. Good knowledge in report writing and assisting with preparing presentations for client status meetings

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Transportation Engineer**

08/2017 - present

- Boles, Smyth Associates, Civil Engineering Consulting Firm, Philadelphia, PA
- Developing and analyses of microscopic traffic models using Synchro 10/Sim Traffic
- Data entry for quantities tabulation and project cost estimates using PennDOT AutoTAB web based application
- Preparing utility relocation plans and coordinating with utility companies
- Performing Crash data analysis and providing recommendations in Crash report
- Good knowledge in layer controlling and developing drawing figures using AutoCAD Civil 3D 2017
- Performing traffic signal warrant analysis, turn lane analysis and using results in Roadway plans

# Transportation Modeling and Analysis intern

01/2017 - 07/2017

- Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission, PA (Metropolitan Planning Organization)
- Forecasting zonal household population data to future years using R programming language
- Air quality planning for 9 counties in Pennsylvania and New Jersey states.
- Vehicle Mile Travelled analysis with integrated use of ArcGIS and PTV Visum
- Import traffic counts data and perform micro simulation using Vissim
- Vehicle speeds data collection for Pottstown bridge feasibility analysis

### **Systems Administrator** – Biology, Utah State University

08/2015-12/2016

Monitoring, updating, repairing hardware, setup security services for all computers in Biology department.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree – Transportation Systems EngineeringDecember 2016Utah State University, Logan UTGPA 3.33Bachelor's Degree – Civil EngineeringMay 2014SRM University, India (ABET- accredited)GPA 3.72

#### Software Skills

PTV Visum 12.5 AutoCAD Civil 3D 2017

ArcGIS 10.3.1 R Studio Synchro 10/Sim Traffic Python

VISSIM Microsoft Office 2016

Adobe Creative Suite MySQL

#### Related Coursework at Utah State University-

Transportation Network Analysis Geometric Design of Highways

Transportation Data and Safety GIS of Civil Engineers

Transportation Systems Analysis Advanced GIS and Spatial Analysis

Urban and Regional Transportation Planning
Traffic Engineering
Hydro Informatics
Earthquake Engineering

# Coursework Projects at Utah State University

Designed one-mile long urban highway for Cedar City, Utah

Optimization of bus and rail routes in transit corridor

Salt Lake County Crash data analysis 2009-2010

# **Professional Memberships**

Affiliate member of American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE)